<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rendering Equations</title>
    <link>https://schuttejoe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rendering Equations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 14:04:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://schuttejoe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling the Solid Angle of Area Light Sources</title>
      <link>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/arealightsampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 14:04:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/arealightsampling/</guid>
      <description>$\newcommand{\c}{\textbf{c}}$ $\newcommand{\x}{\textbf{x}}$ $\newcommand{\r}{\textit{r}}$ $\newcommand{\w}{\hat{\omega}}$ $\newcommand{\a}{\hat{\textit{a}}}$ $\newcommand{\n}{\hat{\textit{n}}}$ $\newcommand{\v}{\hat{\textit{v}}}$ $\newcommand{\d}{\hat{\textit{d}}}$ $\newcommand{\u}{\hat{\textit{u}}}$ $\newcommand{\thetamax}{\theta_{max}}$
With ray tracing mania taking over thanks to the announcement of DXR now seems like a great time for me to write about the next subject I wanted to write about: sampling the solid angle of area lights. While the concept was described in research at least two decades ago I&amp;rsquo;ve found that most books and blog posts that mention sampling area lights tend to describe sampling the surface area of the light source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance Sampling techniques for GGX with Smith Masking-Shadowing: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/ggximportancesamplingpart2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:06:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/ggximportancesamplingpart2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1 of this post I showed a common method for importance sampling the GGX distribution of normals using the inverse of the CDF of the distribution. While this clearly converged faster than importance sampling a cosine lobe it did still leave a number of fireflys in the image that would be pesky to deal with. Additionally, there is a hidden inefficency that is causing us to potentially waste a number of samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance Sampling techniques for GGX with Smith Masking-Shadowing: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/ggximportancesamplingpart1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:38:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/ggximportancesamplingpart1/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about importance sampling the GGX BRDF. GGX used with the Smith masking-shadowing function has become ubiquious in the game industry so it was the first specular model I wanted to implement in the path tracer I&amp;rsquo;m writing. About two weeks before I wrote this blog post I sat down and googled &amp;ldquo;importance sampling ggx&amp;rdquo; and while I was able to find a number of articles and papers that described specific details of the technique I was left a little unsure about whether I was combining the pieces together correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super quick intro</title>
      <link>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 10:06:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schuttejoe.github.io/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>My name is Joe Schutte and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a graphics and engine programmer in the game industry for a bit over ten years now. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been dedicating a significant amount of my spare time towards reading research papers with a focus on rendering for film as well as writing an offline renderer using what I&amp;rsquo;ve read about. This blog will be a medium for me to write about any interesting subject that I encounter and believe might be helpful to share with others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>